<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>post on Lucas Zhu</title><link>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in post on Lucas Zhu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>我傾聽、我觀察、我感受、我紀錄</title><link>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/openthedoor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/openthedoor/</guid><description>曾經我遠離社交軟體，因為那塊土地上發生的事情讓我悲痛、無力、難捱和恐懼。我自私地想無視這一切，但是我做不到，我沒法完全地逃避，而且與親歷者所經受的苦難相比，我所承受的不過萬分之一。也正是因為我只是個幸存者和旁觀者，現在相反地，我回來了，我的反應沒有改變，我的血液還會蒸發但我會去全然擁抱聽到的和看到的所有。你們的故事就是我的故事，我傾聽、我觀察、我感受、我紀錄，也希望有一天，我發聲。我不勇敢，始終不覺得自己在一個合適的位置上能夠公開地講出心中的一切，但是我會走到那一天的，那時候，我會講得很大聲。
「我想看看妞妞
我想上廁所
我剛才量了量體溫 39.4-38.6
我想吃柿子
我去學校的時候夢見奶奶了
我以後吃東西是不是都吃不出味了」</description></item><item><title>I want to tell this to you.</title><link>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/workplace/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/workplace/</guid><description>I thought my career was off a good start. Oh, how wrong and naive I was! Something disturbing and unethical happend in my workplace. Since it&amp;rsquo;s not my story and it&amp;rsquo;s not directly related to me, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have the right to publicly open anyone else&amp;rsquo;s can of worms. However, I want to tell this to you, and I will when it&amp;rsquo;s appropriate, if then, I need your voice.</description></item><item><title>The lows are so extreme, that the good seems fucking cheap.</title><link>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/quitsns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/quitsns/</guid><description>I quit Chinese socail networking sites a long time ago because I selfishly thought the negative effects of using SNS like Weibo outweighed happiness and well-being it brought me. However, expectedly, some major events pop up on my timeline on the other platforms I use and follow because I still want to have a tether, a connection to the people who raised me, who I trust and love. Recently, I saw a helpless little girl in Chengdu sitting on the ground without being accompanied by her parent, holding a bag of instant noodles during quaratine.</description></item><item><title>每一個明天</title><link>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/tomorrow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/tomorrow/</guid><description>結伴創將來 多麼的美
你的路 我的途 再也不分己與彼
有浪有風來 不捨不棄 每一明天也贈你</description></item><item><title>Wuhan - Shanghai</title><link>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/shanghai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/shanghai/</guid><description>Two years later. What&amp;rsquo;s new?</description></item><item><title>Why do I name myself Lucas?</title><link>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/lucas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lucaszhu97.github.io/post/lucas/</guid><description>Psalms 139:9-10
If I rise on the wings of the dawn, if I settle on the far side of the sea, even there your hand will guide me, your right hand will hold me fast.</description></item></channel></rss>